They're not bad. They're just born that way.
Descendants is a family, adventure, fantasy film directed by Kenny Ortega.
A present-day idyllic kingdom where the benevolent teenage son of King Adam and Queen Belle offers a chance of redemption for the
troublemaking offspring of Disney's classic villains: Cruella De Vil (Carlos), Maleficent (Mal), the Evil Queen (Evie) and Jafar (Jay).
Mal, played by Dove Cameron.
Ben, played by Mitchell Hope.
Evie, played by Sofia Carson.
Carlos, played by Cameron Boyce.
Chad Charming, played by Jedidiah Goodacre.
Jay, played by Booboo Stewart.
Descendants is an American musical fantasy television film
directed and choreographed by Kenny Ortega.
The film stars Dove Cameron, Sofia Carson, Booboo Stewart, and Cameron Boyce as the teenage
children of Maleficent, the Evil Queen, Jafar, and Cruella de Vil, respectively.
The film follows these teenagers adjusting to life outside their island prison, while on a
mission to steal the Fairy Godmother's wand and free their parents from captivity.
It debuted on July 31, 2015, as a Disney Channel Original
Movie, to positive reviews and 6.6 million viewers.
The film also stars Mitchell Hope, Melanie Paxson, Brenna D'Amico, Sarah Jeffery, Zachary Gibson, Jedidiah Goodacre, Dianne
Doan, Dan Payne, Keegan Connor Tracy, Wendy Raquel Robinson, Maz Jobrani, Kathy Najimy, and Kristin Chenoweth.
The first installment in the Descendants franchise, Descendants was spun off into several television series, short films, and television specials, including an animated short-form series titled Descendants: Wicked World, and was followed
by a sequel, Descendants 2, which premiered on July 21, 2017, a third film, Descendants 3, which premiered on August 2, 2019, and a fourth film, Descendants: The Rise of Red, which premiered on July 12, 2024 on Disney+.
The film explores themes of witch, high school, magic, fairy tale, villain.
The tone is lighthearted.